Clyde Robert Bulla Papers
University of Minnesota Libraries
Clyde Robert Bulla Papers
1955-1984
University of Minnesota Libraries Children's Literature Research Collections
Bulla, Clyde Robert
CLRC-1945
The collection consists of production material for 20 titles, including typescripts, proofs, notes, articles and photographs.
unknown
Important Information for Users of the Collections
Access and Use:
Collection is open for researchers with no restrictions. Registration with the collection is required.
Biographical Sketch
Clyde Robert Bulla was born in 1914 on a farm near King City, MO. In his early years he attended a one room school house run by his older sister. He attended one year of high school before dropping out to help his family on the farm. He completed his education by correspondence. Although he wanted to be a writer, he was a farmer on his family farm until 1942. Then his father died and the family moved into town. He was a linotype operator and newspaper columnist until1947. From 1947 on he was a writer of children's books. Biographical Source: Something About the Author, v. 139, pp. 45-49.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of production material for twenty titles, including typescripts, proofs, notes, articles and photographs.
Indexing Terms
The collection is indexed under the following headings in the catalog of the University of Minnesota Libraries. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Bulla, Clyde Robert
Accession Information:
Clyde Robert Bulla contributed the collection in the 1960s, 1970s and the early 1980s.
Gift of: Bulla, Clyde Robert
Arrangement
articles and photographs
Benito, 1961
Cardboard Crown, 1984
Charlie's House, 1983
Conquista!, 1978
Daniel's Duck, 1979
Dexter, 1973
Jonah and the Great Fish, 1970
Joseph the Dreamer, 1971
Last Look, 1979
Moon Singer, 1969
Open the Door and See All the People, 1972
Poor Boy, Rich Boy, 1982
Poppy Seeds, 1955
Ring and the Fire, 1962
Shoeshine Girl, 1975
Stories of Gilbert and Sullivan Operas, 1968
Sugar Pear Tree, 1961
Tree is a Plant, 1960
Viking Adventure, 1963
What Makes a Shadow?, 1962
Collection Contents
- articles and photographs
  - typescript, 1 p. (Box MF 159)
  - greeting cards (Box MF 159)
- Benito, 1961
  Angelo, Valenti
  New York: Crowell, 1961
  - typescript, corrected, 63 p. (Box MF 159)
  - notes, 1 p. (Box MF 159)
- Cardboard Crown, 1984
  Chessare, Michele
  New York: Crowell, 1984
  - typescript, corrected with front matter, 8 p., 45 p. (Box MF 1194)
  - galley proof, corrected photocopy, 57 p. (Box MF 1194)
  - page proof, corrected, 79 p. (Box MF 1194)
- Charlie's House, 1983
  Dorros, Arthur
  New York: Crowell, 1983
  - typescript, corrected with front matter, 7 p., 52 p. (Box MF 1194)
  - galley proof, photocopy, 31 p. (Box MF 1194)
  - miscellaneous, 2 p. (Box MF 1194)
- Conquista!, 1978
  Himler, Ronald
  New York: Crowell, 1978
  - typescript, corrected with front matter, 6 p., 19 p. (Box MF 159)
- Daniel's Duck, 1979
  Sandin, Joan
  New York: Harper and Row, 1979
  - typescript, corrected with front matter, 3 p., 11 p. (Box MF 159)
- Dexter, 1973
  Coalson, Glo
  New York: Crowell, 1973
  - typescript, corrected with front matter, 6 p., 60 p. (Box MF 159)
  - galley proof, corrected, 38 p. (Box MF 159)
  - galley proof, corrected, 22 p. (Box MF 159)
  - galley proof, 33 p. (Box MF 159)
- Jonah and the Great Fish, 1970
  Aichinger, Helga
  New York: Crowell, 1970
  - typescript, corrected, 12 p. (Box MF 159)
  - galley proof, corrected, 4 p. (Box MF 159)
- Joseph the Dreamer, 1971
  Laite, Gordon
  New York: Crowell, 1971
  - typescript, corrected, 21 p. (Box MF 159)
  - galley proof, corrected, 27 p. (Box MF 159)
- Last Look, 1979
  McCully, Emily Arnold
  New York: Crowell, 1979
  - typescript, corrected photocopy with front matter, 6 p., 51 p. (Box MF 159)
- Moon Singer, 1969
  Hyman, Trina Schart
  New York: Crowell, 1969
  - typescript, corrected, 14 p. (Box MF 159)
  - galley proof, corrected, 7 p. (Box MF 159)
  - page proof, 27 p. (Box MF 159)
- Open the Door and See All the People, 1972
  Watson, Wendy
  New York: Crowell, 1972
  - typescript, corrected with front matter, 2 p., 44 p. (Box MF 160)
  - galley proof, corrected, 14 p. (Box MF 160)
- Poor Boy, Rich Boy, 1982
  Sewell, Marcia
  New York: Harper and Row, 1982
  - dummy photocopy, 58 p. (Box MF 1194)
- Poppy Seeds, 1955
  Charlot, Jean
  New York: Crowell, 1955
  - typescript, corrected, 12 p. (Box MF 160)
- Ring and the Fire, 1962
  Ross, Clare and John
  New York: Crowell, 1962
  - typescript, corrected with front matter, 5 p., 157 p. (Box MF 160)
  - layout sketch for casts of characters, 1 p.
  - typescript and score for themes from the operas, 13 p. (Box MF 160)
  - typescript for index, 6 p. (Box MF 160)
  - galley proof, 41 p. (Box MF 160)
- Shoeshine Girl, 1975
  Grant, Leigh
  New York: Crowell, 1975
  - typescript, corrected with front matter, 4 p., 60 p. (Box MF 160)
  - page proof, corrected photocopy, 48 p. (Box MF 160)
- Stories of Gilbert and Sullivan Operas, 1968
  McCrea, James and Ruth
  New York: Crowell, 1968
  - typescript, corrected, 263 p. (Box MF 160, 161)
  - galley proof, 68 p. (Box MF 160, 161)
  - page proof, 125 p. (Box MF 160, 161)
- Sugar Pear Tree, 1961
  Yashima, Taro
  - typescript, corrected, 47 p. (Box MF 161)
  - notes, 1 p. (Box MF 161)
- Tree is a Plant, 1960
  Lignell, Lois
  New York: Crowell, 1960
  - typescript, corrected, 4 p. (Box MF 161)
  - notes, 1 p. (Box MF 161)
- Viking Adventure, 1963
  Gorsline, Douglas
  New York: Crowell, 1963
  - galley proof, corrected, 38 p. (Box MF 161)
  - typescript, corrected, 107 p. (Box MF 161)
  - notes, 1 p. (Box MF 161)
- What Makes a Shadow?, 1962
  Adams, Adrienne
  - typescript, corrected, 3 p. (Box MF 161)
  - galley proof, corrected, 2 p. (Box MF 161)
  - galley proof, corrected, 2 p. (Box MF 161)
  - galley proof, corrected, 1 p. (Box MF 161)